<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Harun Reşit Zafer]]></title>
  <link href="http://hrzafer.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://hrzafer.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-08-31T20:03:21+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://hrzafer.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Harun Reşit Zafer]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[harunzafer@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress 'Invalid Byte Sequence in UTF-8' Error With the Rake Generate Command]]></title>
    <link href="http://hrzafer.github.io/octopress-invalid-byte-sequence-error-for-UTF-8-with-the-rake-generate-command"/>
    <updated>2014-08-10T15:15:00+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://hrzafer.github.io/octopress-invalid-byte-sequence-error-for-UTF-8-with-the-rake-generate-command</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is my first post on this blog. Since it was going to be mostly about my work on Github, I decided to publish it on GitHub and naturally this made me choose <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a>. After <a href="http://www.techelex.org/setup-octopress-on-windows7/">installing and deploying octopress</a> successfully, I just wanted to edit <code>_config.yml</code> to set my name for the <code>author</code> and <code>title</code> properties. As my name (Harun Reşit Zafer) has the non-ascii <code>ş</code> in it when I try to run the <code>rake generate</code> command, I got the <code>invalid byte sequence in UTF-8</code> error.</p>

<p>After some googling I found several pages that all suggest creating some system (or environment on Windows) variables called <code>LANG</code>, <code>LC_ALL</code> and <code>LC_CTYPE</code> and set their value to <code>en_US.UTF-8</code>. However it didn&rsquo;t help me. Then I also realized that either on Linux or Windows creating such system variables hadn&rsquo;t helped some other users too.</p>

<p>Then I just opened the <code>_config.yml</code> with Notepad++, changed the encoding to <code>UTF-8 without BOM</code>. As I changed the encoding, the <code>ş</code> character corrupted. I fixed it and saved the file. I got no error when I run the <code>rake generate</code> command this time.</p>

<p>This solution also works for the post files (the ones with <code>.markdown</code> extensions in <code>source/_posts</code> folder). In short, just change the file&rsquo;s encoding <code>UTF-8 without BOM</code> before inserting any non-ascii characters. There is no need for the environment variables in my case.</p>

<p>I hope my first post helps those having the same issue. Please let me know if this works for you too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
